<measure>
  <schema_version>3.0</schema_version>
  <name>hvac_integrated_waterside_economizer</name>
  <uid>51a782df-1990-4035-ace5-811ad2b2cba6</uid>
  <version_id>222dfcd1-3e70-42ad-8f5c-10d9230286ed</version_id>
  <version_modified>20200427T221806Z</version_modified>
  <xml_checksum>48FEEDDD</xml_checksum>
  <class_name>HVACIntegratedWatersideEconomizer</class_name>
  <display_name>IntegratedWatersideEconomizer</display_name>
  <description>This energy efficiency measure (EEM) adds a variable speed drive (VSD) to existing constant-speed, single-stage cooling rooftop units (RTUs). The VSD reduces the fan speed when the RTU is in economizer or ventilation mode, saving energy compared to a constant-speed fan baseline where the fan is run at 100% flow regardless of need.</description>
  <modeler_description>This EEM adds EMS logic to the model for each appropiate airloop object found. The added logic first defines fan speed modifier values based on the unit mode (0.9 for heating, 0.9 for cooling, 0.75 for economizing, 0.4 for ventilation) and a fan power exponent (2.2). The code then checks the heating and cooling runtime fractions and the outdoor air (OA) mass flow rate at each time step. The runtime fractions and OA mass flow rate values are used to determine the percentage of the time step that the unit spends in each mode (heating, cooling, economizing, or ventilation). The mode percentages are then used with the fan speed modifiers and fan power exponent value to calculate a weighted average fan pressure rise for the entire time step. Note that this will affect the fan power for the time step, but does not change the fan flow rate and thus will not affect zone thermal or comfort performance.</modeler_description>
  <arguments/>
  <outputs/>
  <provenances/>
  <tags>
    <tag>Whole Building.Space Types</tag>
  </tags>
  <attributes>
    <attribute>
      <name>Measure Type</name>
      <value>ModelMeasure</value>
      <datatype>string</datatype>
    </attribute>
    <attribute>
      <name>Intended Software Tool</name>
      <value>Apply Measure Now</value>
      <datatype>string</datatype>
    </attribute>
    <attribute>
      <name>Intended Software Tool</name>
      <value>OpenStudio Application</value>
      <datatype>string</datatype>
    </attribute>
    <attribute>
      <name>Intended Software Tool</name>
      <value>Parametric Analysis Tool</value>
      <datatype>string</datatype>
    </attribute>
    <attribute>
      <name>Intended Software Tool</name>
      <value>Analysis Spreadsheet</value>
      <datatype>string</datatype>
    </attribute>
  </attributes>
  <files>
    <file>
      <version>
        <software_program>OpenStudio</software_program>
        <identifier>1.7.2</identifier>
        <min_compatible>1.7.2</min_compatible>
      </version>
      <filename>measure.rb</filename>
      <filetype>rb</filetype>
      <usage_type>script</usage_type>
      <checksum>7EB5FCB1</checksum>
    </file>
    <file>
      <filename>hvac_waterside_economizer_test.rb</filename>
      <filetype>rb</filetype>
      <usage_type>test</usage_type>
      <checksum>90B6105D</checksum>
    </file>
  </files>
</measure>
