<measure>
  <schema_version>3.0</schema_version>
  <name>hvac_variable_speed_cooling_tower</name>
  <uid>8da9ee06-9749-4b01-a1c0-bb4666a6d800</uid>
  <version_id>302ed2e5-18fa-407f-8134-15f8bd23a244</version_id>
  <version_modified>20200430T203512Z</version_modified>
  <xml_checksum>F27B6ED6</xml_checksum>
  <class_name>HVACVariableSpeedCoolingTower</class_name>
  <display_name>add_cooling_tower_controls</display_name>
  <description>This energy efficiency measure (EEM) replaces each existing cooling tower object present in an OpenStudio model with a CoolingTower:VariableSpeed object. While many of the existing cooling tower attributes are persisted, the following tower performance attributes will be changed:  Create and apply a theoretical fan curve where fan power ratio is directly proportional to the air flow rate ratio cubed, set Minimum Air Flow Rate Ratio to 20%, set Evaporation Loss Mode to ?Saturated Exit?, set Drift Loss Percent to 0.05, set Blowdown Calculation mode to ?ConcentrationRatio? and set Blowdown Concentration Ratio to 3.0.</description>
  <modeler_description>This energy efficiency measure (EEM) replaces all cooling tower objects in a model of the following types: (OS:CoolingTowerPerformanceCoolTools, OS:CoolingTowerPerformanceYorkCalc,  OS:CoolingTowerSingleSpeed, OS:CoolingTowerTwoSpeed, or OS:CoolingTowerVariableSpeed) with a new OS:CoolingTower:VariableSpeed object. If an existing cooling tower is already configured for variable speed, the measure will inform the user. When replacing an existing tower object, the following values from the existing tower configuration will be reused: Design Inlet Air Wet Bulb Temp, Design Approach Temperature, Design Range Temperature, Design Water Flow Rate, Design Air Flow Rate, Design Fan Power, Fraction of Tower Capacity in the Free Convection Regime, Basin Heater Capacity,  Basin Heater Setpoint Temperature, Basin Heater Operating Schedule, Number of Cells,  Cell Control, Cell Minimum and Maximum Water Flow Rate Fractions and Sizing Factor. A performance curve relating fan power to tower airflow rates is used. The curve assumes the fan power ratio is directly proportional to the air flow rate ratio cubed. A Minimum Air Flow Rate Ratio of 20% will be set. To model minimal but realistic water consumption, the Evaporation Loss Mode for new Tower objects will be set to ?Saturated Exit? and Drift Loss Percent will be set to a value of 0.05% of the Design Water Flow.  Blowdown water usage will be based on maintaining a Concentration Ratio of 3.0.</modeler_description>
  <arguments>
    <argument>
      <name>run_measure</name>
      <display_name>Run Measure</display_name>
      <description>integer argument to run measure [1 is run, 0 is no run]</description>
      <type>Integer</type>
      <required>true</required>
      <model_dependent>false</model_dependent>
      <default_value>1</default_value>
    </argument>
  </arguments>
  <outputs/>
  <provenances/>
  <tags>
    <tag>HVAC.Heat Rejection</tag>
  </tags>
  <attributes>
    <attribute>
      <name>Measure Type</name>
      <value>ModelMeasure</value>
      <datatype>string</datatype>
    </attribute>
    <attribute>
      <name>Intended Software Tool</name>
      <value>Apply Measure Now</value>
      <datatype>string</datatype>
    </attribute>
    <attribute>
      <name>Intended Software Tool</name>
      <value>OpenStudio Application</value>
      <datatype>string</datatype>
    </attribute>
    <attribute>
      <name>Intended Software Tool</name>
      <value>Parametric Analysis Tool</value>
      <datatype>string</datatype>
    </attribute>
    <attribute>
      <name>Intended Use Case</name>
      <value>Model Articulation</value>
      <datatype>string</datatype>
    </attribute>
  </attributes>
  <files>
    <file>
      <filename>hvac_var_speed_cooling_tower_test.rb</filename>
      <filetype>rb</filetype>
      <usage_type>test</usage_type>
      <checksum>5BBF9934</checksum>
    </file>
    <file>
      <version>
        <software_program>OpenStudio</software_program>
        <identifier>1.8.0</identifier>
        <min_compatible>1.8.0</min_compatible>
      </version>
      <filename>measure.rb</filename>
      <filetype>rb</filetype>
      <usage_type>script</usage_type>
      <checksum>F3ACC24F</checksum>
    </file>
  </files>
</measure>
